Hello, all my friends, and welcome to exercise number 100, yes, 100 you solved 100 exercise and
data structures and algorithms.
So in this exercise, we are going to make and implement the heap in Java.
So I will go to the RC here code.
I will create a new Java class called him.
So we need to create many methods inside the heap like, insert, defy, answer.
So if you want all of these source codes, you can download them from the resources folder under each
question and each exercise.
So this is the class.
I will start with a method called hip ify.
So void, public
public void Apisai
it took into the parametres array last.
Having in genetics, as in Tiger, it's called Étudie and I, we said we said that typify that at range,
the numbers there were is that the parent is the minimum and the children as the are the maximum so
that children are greater than their parents.
OK.
This is the proof.
So please go back to the previous videos to learn about hip ify and they're here to take that structure.
OK.
So actually got.
The size we get the size first, and we start by making inthe largest equal to I.
And in an equal to two times, I this is the logic that we have seen it and ask people to do two times
I plus do.
Yes.
And less than size and at the get lowest l greater than Edge did not get larger
than what to do.
We are going to set the largest equal to Earth health if you are less than size and actually don't get
are greater than achieve, don't get largest.
Then what to do?
Largest equal to.
OK, OK.
So this is the case that we check for the largest and we have assigned the L and R two variables.
If this condition is true, then making the largest equal to.
And if this song had this condition is true, then make are just equal to.
OK, now if largest does not equal, do I then what to do
and to give them equal to actually get largest?
And the third set not just to get high.
And D that said, I do that, we pass it again to that.
OK.
These are the two functions now here, April five.
This is the recursion, and we said that we use the recursion in order to deal with the hip ify.
And we passed that largest until reaching that L or art and design thinking, OK, if Florida does not
equal to II, then we make that hip ify again and we call this recursive function.
Now, let's make an insert function and delete node function.
Here.
If this is for a hit before I know insert, you know, into the hip, so public void insert, we took
into the parameters that had a list of type integer.
We are dealing with integer array list and Int Newnam, and we start by making int size equal to achieve
that size.
If size equal equal to zero, then what to do at the dock?
Add this is very simple.
One.
OK.
Else what to do?
We need to add each did not add new number.
This is the new norm, and we are going to add that number.
This is if the size equal equal to zero empty.
This is the case of empty heap.
If there is another elements, we need to insert the new number in it in its correct condition.
That's correct situation and a place.
So we need to make a heap ify so far that we need to start by for low and equal to size over due minus
one I greater than or equal to zero and a minus points
here before we start by calling the method PHI, and we passed that on again and again until we reach
a stop income.
So we see guys how this algorithms work.
We start by checking it is an empty.
He then added the new otherwise, if it is not a new element and not an empty heap and a new element
would be inserted, then we add it and we start by typifying ET and until we can add the new number.
OK, and we hit wi fi on this.
Now, in case we are going to delete a node, we need also to be fi.
So void the public
avoid delete node we took into the parameter array lest it take into that genetic type and numb and
and size be equal to actually that size.
We get the size of this and then we make an entire AI and risk type or a for loop here for.
For we can get it back, and I it's not racialized for equal to zero.
I am less than size and I plus glass.
We need to make if check no equal equals tragedy to get I.
We need to check this present inside the hip, then break.
OK, now.
We have checked if it is here, so in and equal to actually don't get high and edge the set here, I
first I had etched the gap size minus one again.
Actually, the set size minus one and passed the tank.
OK, here etched the door to remove size minus one.
OK.
This is what we have to remove the size minus one.
And here we need to be.
Is that the hip again because we have removed a an element from it?
So size over two over to minus one
j.
The greater than or equal to zero.
And the J minus minus here.
Big I etched the and this time we passed the J.
OK.
This is that the the difference between this delete note and that insert note in terms of hip ify,
we start by pressing that element of the index that we are going to pass it in the look.
Now let's print the hip by making public void trend of a of a list.
Erm, T-shirt out of there
and size and making an integer I for every element inside this array that we have passed and what we
need from this to be, we need to print it out.
So we are printing this object type integer because we have made it as an integer object here.
This is by using their app for classes.
And here we print out the new line.
This is a print array that we have created many times and in all of the cluster pictures.
Now let's make the driven, class driven method the main, and we check our code so string here parks.
We create an array list of type of diet parameter integer Atalay equal to new array list, and we pass
an integer here
and we start in size equal to as a dot size.
Now.
Let's create the heap.
So here is an object of here at equal to you here.
That's dug insert, we need to insert the elements we passed, the rate that we have created and where
we insert the new element, the new number here.
Three, four, nine five.
Do let us remove this.
So system that out, the brain and Max
here, as there is by calling at Stoke on Trent that they pass that ray and the size of that.
OK.
This is how we test our code.
Let's run our main method here.
And here we go, guys, we have.
Correctly insert maximum here created the maximum heat as a hip array, a nine, five, three, four
and two.
This is our hip.
This is our hip data structure that we have created in Java and in next exercises, we are going to
deal with the here and later on.
We are going to go deeply inside the hip and solve many exercises about it.
So I hope you're right as five stars when you do me and support us by sharing.